

Berkay Oztürk Game Developer

About me

Date of birth: 13.10.1996

I have a very active personality and I love interacting with people. What motivates me to research, create things and solve problems is my curiosity. I love working with teams because I believe that is when one can go beyond themselves. I respect the work of my teammates and I know it is an important part of teamwork. That's why I am interested with free software movement. People always told me that I have good managerial skills while directing the free software society in Bilkent and I believe we did some great things in that period. I want to improve myself as a game designer because I love seeing reactions that I get when I create an experience through games that I design.

Language Skills

Turkish, Native English, Proficient

Software Skills

Unity3D, Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, GarageBand.

Personal Interests

Sound Design, UI/UX Design, Hardware Development. I am also interested in drumming, snowboarding, kite surfing, sailing and juggling.

Contact

e-mail: bberkayozturk@gmail.com address: Mustafa Kemal Mahallesi

Ankara-Ankara Sitesi

C Blok Daire 5 Çankaya / Ankara mobile: +90 (538) 248 28 24 website: berkaay.github.io portfolio: berkaay.itch.io

Education

Bilkent University Computer Technology and Information Systems B.Sc. Degree

CGPA: 3.0/4.0 2014-2018

Gazi University Foundation High School

CGPA: 86.5/100 2010-2014

Experience

Internships



Özgür Yazılım A.Ş. July 2016 to August 2016

I served my 1,5 months internship doing frontend and backend web development. We used Wordpress and PHP. I delivered the implementation of the web design for a customer. I have improved my skills in Linux, PHP, Wordpress, and Git.



Istanbul

Dell EMC February 2017 to June 2017

I served my 1-semester internship as an assistant for the Pre-sales team for a hyper-converged infrastructure appliance. I did plenty of presentations and product installments. I have improved my knowledge in Cloud Infrastructure, server management, Linux and virtualization. I have adapted to the corporate workflow.

Communities



Chairman - Bilkent Free Software Society

I have organized activities and tutorials to support free software movement. I gave tutorials for Introduction to Linux. I organized the event "Internet Haftasi" which had 7 speakers on free software and history of the internet in Turkey.



Active Member - IEEE Student Branch

I was involved in the organization of Mobile Days for 2 years. I was responsible for the relations with the sponsors of the event.

BGD Active Member - Bilkent Game Developers

I have attended to game jams and tutorials. I developed my first game prototype in Unity getting help from the people in this society.

Projects

Engage 2018

Senior Project



Engage is a mobile multiplayer game platform. I have worked with a partner in this project. I was responsible for the UI/UX design of the app. Game design of the mini-games in the app and also developing the native app. I also designed posters logos and developed the brand of iOS App the app overall. I gained some experience with GameSparks as well. We have won the "Most Innovative Project" award from our department.

Gravy 2017

Side Project

Gravy is my first game prototype. I both developed and designed the game. I used Unity3D for implementation.

Mini games with OpenGL 2017 & 2018 Lecture Project I have implemented some mini-games using GLUT with C++ to improve my graphical programming skills. The projects have lightning, shaders, 3D models and animations implemented.

3rd Wave Coffee Finder 2017

Lecture Project

I have created a native iOS app made with Swift which finds 3rd wave coffee shops near you.

I Have Been There 2016

Lecture Project

I have created a native Android app made with Java where you add your favorite locations in the city. It uses Google's Maps API.

Pixel Art Maker 2016

Lecture Project

I have implemented a very basic pixel art maker for game designers using Java. Used Java AWT GUI Library and OOP concepts.